翻译: AT Arling 绵绵虫 叶子
校对: 安宝
后期: Nico
压制: 怪查理
总监: 怪查理
电波字幕组
诚心诚译
青   春   年   少
当且仅当两端的分子
If, and only if, both sides of the numerator is divisible by
都能被这两个未知变量的平方根的倒数整除时
the inverse of the square root of the two unassigned variables.
很好 除了当X轴上的坐标值
Good. Except when the value of the "X" Coordinate...
小于等于1的时候
is equal to or less than the value of one.
- 怎么了 Isaac  - 那道题怎么了
- Yes, Isaac? - What about that problem?
哦 那个啊 不用去想那题 "M"是
Oh, that? Don't worry about that. "M" Is
等等 为什么
Wait. Why?
我就写着玩的
I just put that up as a joke.
那大概是全世界最难的几何方程式了
That's probably the hardest geometry equation in the world.
解出来能得多少额外学分呢
How much extra credit is it worth?
这个嘛 鉴于我还没见任何人答对过
Well, considering I've never seen anyone get it right...
包括我在麻省理工的导师 Leaky博士
including my mentor, Dr. Leaky at M.I.T....
在座任何一位能解答出来的人
I guess if anyone here can solve that problem.
我敢肯定
I'd see to it that
余生都不需要再学数学了
none of you ever have to open another math book again for the rest of your lives.
Max
Max?
你想试试吗
Care to try it?
抱歉 是有人叫了我的名字吗
I'm sorry. Did someone say my name?
你解出来了
You got it.
Fischer Fischer Fischer Fischer Fischer
Fischer! Fischer! Fischer! Fischer! Fischer!
谢谢
Thank you.
你们拥有的一切都来得轻而易举
You guys have it real easy.
我不曾拥有这样的成长环境
I never had it like this where I grew up.
但我把我的孩子送到这里
But I send my kids here because, the fact is...
因为这里是全国最好的学校之一
you go to one of the best schools in the country:
拉什莫尔
Rushmore.
对于你们中的某些人来说
Now, for some of you,
这并不重要
it doesn't matter.
你们含着金汤匙出生 将世代富有
You were born rich, and you're going to stay rich.
但对于另外一部分人 我的建议是
But here's my advice to the rest of you:
死死瞄准这些富家少爷
Take dead aim on the rich boys.
盯着准星里的每个人
Get them in the crosshairs,
拿下他们
and take them down.
记住
Just remember:
他们虽然在物质上富有一切 但永远买不到骨气
They can buy anything, but they can't buy backbone.
圣诗集
拉什莫尔-全国顶尖名校
有钱小孩-不怎么样？
台上的人
教堂有史以来最好的演讲者
时刻提醒他们这一点
Don't let them forget that.
谢谢
Thank you.
有空来毕业典礼吗 Herman 你可以做个返场演讲
Free for graduation, Herman? Perhaps you could give us an encore.
- Nicholas Copernicus  - 我才不在乎
- Nicholas! Copernicus! - I don't give a shit.
老子出钱建了整个游泳馆
I paid for the whole damn natatorium.
这帮小崽子至少得听我把话说完吧
The least these little pricks can do is hear me out.
- 您好 Guggenheim教授  - 你好 Max
- Hi, Dr. Guggenheim. - Hello, Max.
您好 我是Max Fischer
Hello. I'm Max Fischer.
我只想跟您说 我非常赞同您对拉什莫尔的观点
I just wanted to say that I strongly agree with your views concerning Rushmore.
还有 您的演讲非常精彩
Um... your speech was excellent.
- 谢谢  - 谢谢您
- Thank you. - Thank you.
- 谢谢  - 您好
- Thank you. - Hello.
噢 Blume先生 他是我的教友 Dirk Calloway
Oh, Mr. Blume, this is my chapel partner, Dirk Calloway.
教友 学院中高年级学生和低年级学生组成的
一同进行祷告颂诗的伙伴关系
幸会 Dirk
Nice to meet you, Dirk.
谢谢
Well, thanks.
那个
You know...
我觉得关于拉什莫尔您讲的太对了
I really think you're right about Rushmore.
走吧 Drik
Come on, Dirk.
- 他叫什么来着  - Max Fischer
- What's his name again? - Max Fischer.
很机灵的小鬼
Sharp little guy.
他是我们这儿最麻烦的学生之一
He's one of the worst students we've got.
背景音乐 <Making Time> - The Creation
拉什莫尔校刊
Max Fischer 总编辑
洋基评论 发行人
法语社 社长
模拟联合国 俄罗斯代表
邮票钱币社 副社长
辩论队 队长
曲棍球队 经纪人
书法社 社长
下午3:30 功夫社将在此举办会议
天文社 创始人
击剑队 队长
田径社
十项全能运动后备队员
第二合唱团 指挥
躲避球社 创始人
你 出局
You! You're out!
功夫社 黄带选手
射击社 创始人
养蜂社 社长
洋基赛车社 创始人
Max Fischer扮演者 导演
轻型飞机社
4.5小时飞行记录保持者
九月
我们将把你列入"紧急留校察看"名单
We're putting you on what we call "Sudden death academic probation."
那是什么意思呢
And what does that entail?
意思就是 要是你再挂一门课 就会被勒令退学
It entails that if you fail another class you'll be asked to leave Rushmore.
换句话说 就是我会被开除
In other words, I'll be expelled.
说对了
That's correct.
我能看看相关的文字档案吗
Could I see some documentation on that, please?
社团活动太多 学习时间太少
Too many extracurricular activities, Max. Not enough studying.
英语3
植物学
戏剧学2
法语3
几何
嗯
Mm-hmm.
Guggenheim教授 不是我对您的工作指手画脚
Dr. Guggenheim, I don't want to tell you how to do your job...
但事实是 无论我多努力学习 还是很可能再挂掉一门课
but the fact is, no matter how hard I try I still might flunk another class.
如果那意味着留级一年 悉听尊便
If that means I have to stay on for a postgraduate year, then so be it,
- 但是  - 我们并没有留级制度
- But... - We don't offer a postgraduate year.
只是此前没有而已
Well... we don't offer it yet.
努把力提高成绩吧
Just bring up the grades.
您还记得我是怎么进入这所学校的吗
Do you remember how I got into this school?
记得 你写了一出话剧
Yes. You wrote a play.
是的 二年级的时候
That's right. Second grade.
我写了一出关于"水门事件"的独幕剧
A little one-act about Watergate.
水门事件 1972年总统大选中尼克松的竞选团队
在水门大厦安装窃听器并偷拍机密文件时当场被捕
我妈妈看了之后觉得我应该去拉什莫尔读书
And my mother read it and felt I should go to Rushmore.
然后您读了剧本 还给了我奖学金 不是吗
And you read it, and you gave me a scholarship, didn't you?
是的
Mm-hmm.
- 您后悔吗  - 不 我不后悔
- Do you regret it? - No, I don't regret it.
但我仍然可能不得不开除你
But I still might have to expel you.
可不可以 可不可以睁一只眼闭一只眼呢
Couldn't Couldn't we just let me float by?
看在往日的情分上
For old time's sake?
不可以 Max
Can't do it, Max.
- 他们想踢我出去  - 不是吧 又来
- They want to kick me out. - Oh, no. Not again.
- 你打算怎么办  - 我想我唯一能做的
- What are you gonna do? - The only thing I can do:
就是争取抱上教务处的大腿
try and pull some strings with the administration, I guess.
西洋双陆棋社
创始人 Max Fischer
比赛中 请保持安静
你听说了下学期要开日语课吗
Did you hear they're teaching Japanese next year?
只是传闻而已
That's the rumor.
- 还要取消拉丁语课  - 什么
- And they're canceling Latin. - What?
我为了取消拉丁语课摇旗呐喊了5年
I tried to get Latin canceled for five years.
"这是一门死去的语言" 我一直这样说
"It's a dead language," I'd always say.
我猜他们总算听到了你的心声吧
Well, I guess they finally heard you.
当一个人有机会开启非凡的一生时
无论如何他都不该埋没自己
失陪一下
Excuse me.
我可不可以看一下
Could I please see a list of all the people
去年借阅这本书的人的名单
who've checked out this book in the past year?
为什么
Why?
看这儿
Look at that.
嗯
Hmm.
Cross小姐
一年级
121教室
"我见的恶徒和愚人都多不胜数
"I have seen wicked men and fools, a great many of both;
我坚信他们最后都将付出代价
and I believe they both get paid in the end.
但愚人会先付出代价
But the fools first.
第十五章 带银色纽扣的少年"
Chapter 15. The Lad with the Silver Button."
- 十分钟后拐角见  - 你要去哪
- Meet me on the corner in 1 0 minutes. - Where are you going?
到巡逻车里再说
I'll tell you in the squad car.
哦 还有 Willie
Oh, and, Willie...
关于Enrique Sanchez的案子你弄错了
you were wrong about Enrique Sanchez.
他是在睡梦里死去的
He died in his sleep.
精彩 真是精彩
Excellent. That was excellent.
太棒了 太棒了
That was great. That was great.
Irving 麻烦你给大家买点根汁汽水吧
Um, Irving. Could you get some root beers for anybody who wants one?
- 我就不要了  - 好的
- I don't want one, okay? - Okay.
好了 下一幕
All right. Next scene.
Frank 你拿一袋可卡因上台
Frank, you enter stage right with a bag of cocaine.
那天我还跟Calloway先生说
I was just telling Mr.Calloway the other day
有你关照Drik 我们真的很省心
how fortunate we are to have someone like you looking out for Dirk.
噢 您太客气了
Oh, don't be silly.
Drik本身就是好孩子
Dirk's a great kid,
我只是再传授一些经验 锦上添花而已
and I'm just trying to impart some of the experiences I've accrued to help him.
这上面有我的号码
This has my number on it,
无论是Drik还是任何需要帮忙的的事情 都可以打电话找我
if you need to call me or need help with Dirk or anything like that.
拉什莫尔学校 23号分机
非常感谢你
Well, thank you very much.
- 哈喽 Drik  - 嗨 妈妈
- Hello, Dirk. - Hi, Mom.
- 怎么样 宝贝  - 我很好
- How are you, honey? - Fine.
- 再见  - 再见 很高兴再次见到你
- Bye. - Bye. It was so nice to see you again.
嘿 Drik 数学测试考得怎么样啊
Hey, Dirk. How'd your math test go?
什么数学测试
What math test?
我还以为你昨天有数学测试呢
I thought you had a math test today.
没有 你那篇写柏林空运的论文交了吗
No. Did you turn in your paper on the Berlin Airlift?
柏林空运 冷战期间苏联封锁德国铁路 英美等盟国空军部队向德国空投物资
是世界历史上规模最大的空中运输行动
嗯 我申请了延期
Yeah, I got an extension.
- 嘿 George  - 和Calloway太太到哪一步了
- Hey, George. - So how'd it go with Mrs. Calloway?
我们握手了
We shook hands.
这有什么
Big deal.
我还给她留了号码
And I gave her my phone number.
Buchan说要是他早就上了她了
Buchan said he'd have already banged her by now.
什么
What?
叫那个苏格兰大猩猩闭上不干不净的臭嘴
Just tell that deformed Scottish gorilla to shut his fat face.
他说的可是我最好朋友的妈妈
That's my best friend's mother he's talking about.
我一直以为那是你选Dirk做你教友的原因呢
I always thought that's why you picked Dirk as your chapel partner.
你谁啊 律师么
What are you, a lawyer?
您好 Blume先生
Hey, Mr. Blume.
您好 我是Max Fischer
Hey. It's Max Fischer.
哦 你好
Oh, hi.
嘿 Max 我妈来了
Hey, Max. My mom just showed up.
我早点走可以吗 完毕
Is it okay if I leave early? Over.
当然可以 Charlie
Sure, Charlie.
你的秘诀是什么 Max
What's the secret, Max?
什么秘诀
"The secret"?
就是 你好像看透一切的样子
Yeah. Well, you seem to have it pretty figured out.
这个啊 我也不知道
The secret. I don't know. Uh
我觉得你只需要找到自己想做的事情
I think you just gotta find something you love to do...
然后终身为之努力就可以了
and then do it for the rest of your life.
对我来说 这件事就是进拉什莫尔
For me, it's going to Rushmore.
- 前排归我  - 嘿 Ronny 嘿 Donny 你们好啊
- Shotgun. - Hey, Ronny. Hey, Donny. How you guys
- 滚到后面去 我说了"前排归我"  - 你就坐后面吧 Donny
- Get in the back. I said "Shotgun." - Get in the back, Donny.
开车吧
Let's go.
- 你们邀请那孩子参加生日聚会了吗  - Max Fischer吗
- Did you invite that kid to your party? - Max Fischer?
拉倒吧老爸 会有女孩子在那儿的 我才不会叫他来
Come on, Dad. There's gonna be girls there. I'd rather die.
脑子糊涂了老头
Pull your head out of your ass.
- 晚安 Littlejeans先生  - 晚安 Max
- Good night, Mr. Littlejeans. - Good night, Max.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
我能看看后面吗
May I see the back, please?
当然可以
Certainly.
觉得怎么样
How's that?
谢谢
Thank you.
顺便说一下 几何试卷上要签个字
I need a signature on this geometry test, by the way.
我瞧瞧
Let's see.
- 嗯  - 我知道 我知道
- Hmm. - I know, I know.
37分
A 37.
哎 我不知道该怎么办了
Oh, I don't know what to do anymore.
本来可能更糟的
It could have been worse.
你差一点就能得A了
You almost got the "A."
什么差点能得A 爸 你写什么呢
"Almost got the 'A"'? Dad, what are you writing?
可能是我花太多时间在创立社团还有话剧上了
Maybe I'm spending too much of my time starting up clubs and putting on plays.
有可能
That's possible.
也许我应该更努力去泡妞
I should probably be trying harder to score chicks.
那才是大家真正在意的唯一一件事
That's the only thing anybody really cares about.
可惜我并不擅长
It's not my forte, unfortunately.
生活就是这样 Max
It'll happen, Max.
你就像那些快帆船的船长
It's just You're like one of those clipper ship captains.
大海是你的宿命
You're married to the sea.
嗯 没错
Yes, that's true.
但我在海上漂流的太久了
But I've been out to sea for a long time.
你好
Hello.
Hi.
我喜欢你的帽子
I like your hat.
噢 谢谢
Oh, thank you.
你是这儿的老师 是吧
You're a teacher here, aren't you?
我猜这是你来拉什莫尔的第一年
And this is your first year at Rushmore, I take it.
是的
Uh-huh.
不介意的话我想问 你抽烟多久了
And how long have you been a smoker, if you don't mind me asking?
我想想
Well, let's see now.
- 你多大了  - 十五
- H-How old are you? - Fifteen.
- 我在你这个年纪就开始抽了  - 不是吧
- Since I was your age. - You're kidding.
你该戒烟了
You should quit.
你说得对
You're right.
我也该少管闲事了
And I should mind my own business.
顺便问一句 你在哪念的大学啊
Where did you go to school, by the way?
- 哈佛  - 真的吗
- Harvard. - Really?
真是巧了
That's a coincidence.
我最想申请的两个学校就是牛津和索邦
My top schools where I want to apply to are Oxford and the Sorbonne.
哈佛保底
My safety's Harvard.
- 很有野心嘛  - 谢谢夸奖
- That's very ambitious. - Thank you.
你想学什么专业
What do you want to study?
这个嘛 我还没完全定下来
Well... I haven't decided for sure...
不过应该是主修数学和医学双学位
but probably a double major in mathematics and premed.
你主修的是什么
What was your major?
我没有主修学科
I didn't have a major,
但我的毕业论文是关于拉丁美洲的经济政策
But my thesis was on Latin American economic policy.
哦 挺有意思的
Oh, that's interesting.
你听说下学期不教拉丁语了吗
Did you hear they're not going to teach Latin here anymore?
这儿更像是中美洲国家
This was more like Central America.
哦 中美国家之类的 嗯
Oh, Central America and whatnot. Hmm.
继续之前的话题 下学期不教拉丁语了
But moving on: They're gonna cancel Latin.
学院打算新开一门日语课
They've got to make room for Japanese.
太遗憾了 因为整个罗曼斯语系都是以拉丁语为基础的
That's a shame because all the Romance languages are based on Latin.
是啊 是这样的 不是吗
Yeah, they are, aren't they?
Nihilo sanctum estne
Nihilo sanctum estne?
什么意思
What's that?
哦 是拉丁语吧 什么意思啊
Oh, it's Latin, isn't it? What does that mean?
没有什么是神圣的了吗
Is nothing sacred?
Sic transit gloria
Sic transit gloria.
荣光已逝
Glory fades.
我叫Max Fischer.
I'm Max Fischer.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hi. - Hi.
背景音乐 <Concrete And Clay> - Unit4+2
- 快 快 快签  - 麻烦签这里
- Come on, come on. File out. - Sign here, please.
- 荣光已逝  - 好 很好
- Sic transit gloria. - All right, all right.
请愿书
最后 我就一个问题
In summation, I have only one question:
拉丁语已死吗
Is Latin dead?
感谢十班学生Max Fischer的努力
拉丁语将成为7至12年级的必修课
你怎么不去死 Fischer 你个低能废物
Why don't you just piss off, Fischer, you dotty wee skid mark?
那句是拉丁语么
Was that Latin?
我怎么也没想过 自己会生出这样的儿子
Never in my wildest imagination did I ever dream I would have sons like these.
你爸爸是做什么工作的 Max
What's your dad do, Max?
他是圣约瑟夫医院的一名神经外科医生
He's a neurosurgeon at, uh, St. Joseph's Hospital.
就我个人而言 我永远做不到剖开某个人的脑袋
Personally, I could never see myself cutting open somebody's brain,
但我爸看上去很享受
but he seems to enjoy it.
哦 不用不用 我来付
Oh, no, no, no. I got this one.
我没记错的话 您参加过越南战争是吗
So you were in Vietnam, if I'm not mistaken?
是的
Yeah.
境遇很糟吗
Were you in the shit?
是的 很糟
Yeah, I was in the shit.
周日见 Blume先生
See you Sunday, Mr. Blume.
好的
All right.
周日有什么事吗
What's on Sunday?
哦 想起来了 是双胞胎的生日聚会
Oh, that's right. The twins' birthday party.
你想来吗
Do you want to come?
我很想去 但我已经有约了
I'd love to, except I've already got a previous obligation to attend to.
不过还是谢谢您的邀请
Yeah. Thanks for the invitation though.
来给我做事吧
Come work for me.
- 什么意思  - 意思就是 我 我能用上你这样的人
- What do you mean? - I mean, I-I-I could use someone like you.
我可能不是什么有钱人 Blume先生
Look, I may not be rich, Mr. Blume.
我爸可能也只是个医生 但我们应付得来
My father may only be a doctor, but we manage.
112号
One-twelves!
失陪了 Blume先生 跟您聊天很愉快
Excuse me, Mr. Blume. Nice talking to you.
你也参加了摔角队吗
You're on the team?
我是替补
I'm an alternate.
最近怎么样 很高兴再次见到你
How you doin'? Good to see you again.
哇 酷毙了
Whoa. Neat.
背景音乐 <Nothin' In The World Can Stop Me worryin' 'Bout That Girl> - The Kinks
Cross小姐
Miss Cross?
我想我应该让你知道 根据我们那天的对话
I thought I'd just let you know as per our conversation the other day
- 拉丁语吗  - 是的 罗曼斯语系
- Latin? - Right. The Romance languages.
- 我做了一个小型演讲  - 我听说了
- Well, I gave a little speech. - I heard about this.
是嘛
Oh, you did?
我知道你说服了大家
I understand you made a very convincing argument.
我只是觉得你听到这个消息会很高兴
I just thought you'd be pleased to hear they're gonna continue the Latin program.
确实让我印象深刻
I'm very impressed.
很感谢你
Well, thank you very much.
嘿 您需要助手吗
Hey, you need an assistant?
这里可以雇用助手吗
Do we get to have an assistant around here?
应该不行吧
No, I doubt it.
我是拿奖学金的 学术奖学金 所以得做一些奇怪的工作
I'm on scholarship though academic scholarship so I get to do odd jobs.
你是怎么决定到拉什莫尔来教书的呢
And Say, how did you decide to teach at Rushmore?
我丈夫先来了这里
My husband went here.
我 我不知道你结婚了
I, uh I didn't know you were married.
他已经去世了
Well, he's dead now.
所以事实上我也不算已婚了
So I'm not, actually.
他什么时候去世的
When did he die?
去年
Last year.
我妈妈也去世了
My mother's dead.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry to hear that.
我7岁那年她就去世了
She died when I was seven.
看来我们家里都有人过世了
I guess we both have dead people in our families.
这里是怎么回事
What's going on in here?
这些小鱼是刚出生的
These were just born.
我不要合金 我要钢材
I don't want alloys. I want steel.
他说什么我才不管
I don't give a rat's ass what he says.
我要钢材 Harry
Steel, Harry.
所以你改主意要来工作了
So you change your mind and you want the job.
不是 但我有个主意 也需要一些资金
No. But I've got an idea, and I need some money.
拉什莫尔需要的是个水族馆
What Rushmore needs is an aquarium
设备一流的水族馆 科学家可以在里面演讲
a first-class aquarium - where the scientists can lecture...
学生也能在自然生态里
and the students can observe
观察海洋动物的生活习性
the marine life in its natural habitat.
我不知道 你觉得呢 Ernie
I don't know. What do you think, Ernie?
一个水族馆 养什么鱼
An aquarium? What kind of fish?
梭鱼 魔鬼鱼 电鳗 鳟鱼
Barracudas, stingrays, electric eel, trout...
锤头鲨 食人鱼 大乌贼 章
hammerheads, piranha, giant squid, octopi -
食人鱼 当真吗
Piranhas? Really?
是的 我在跟一个南美洲的人接洽了
Yes, I'm talking to a guy in South America.
- Guggenheim怎么说  - 什么也没说
- What'd Guggenheim say? - Nothing.
我觉得我应该先跟你讲
I felt I should go to you first.
为什么
Why?
因为在这个阶段
Because at this moment,
我觉得先低调行事为好
I feel the best strategy is to keep it low profile.
事前的准备越充分
The more preparation work I can do...
跟教务处提议的时候
the stronger our case will be
方案就越有说服力
when we take it to the administration.
你想要多少资金
How much money do you want?
就初步计划而言 三万五千美金
$35,000, for the initial plans.
我给你两千五
I'll give you 2,500.
好吧
Okay.
背景音乐 <A Summer Song> - Chad & Jeremy
*树儿*
*Trees*
*随着夏日微风摇曳*
*Swaying in the summer breeze*
*展现出银色的枝叶*
*Showing off their silver leaves*
*当我们悠悠路过*
*As we walked by*
海洋生物第二部
暗礁探索
*轻轻的*
*Soft*
*夏日的亲吻*
*Kisses on a summer's day*
*笑着忘记所有顾虑*
*Laughing all our cares away*
*只剩彼此*
*Just you and I*
*甜蜜*
*Sweet*
*夏夜慵懒的暖意*
*Sleepy warmth of summer nights*
*凝视远处的星空*
*Gazing at the distant lights*
*放出的璀璨光芒*
*In the starry sky*
- 谢谢  - 不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
- Max  - 怎么了
- Max? - Mm-hmm?
- 我可以问你个问题吗  - 当然
- Can I ask you something? - Sure.
你有没想过 你对我来说可能太小了
Has it ever crossed your mind that you're far too young for me?
我确实想过
It crossed my mind that
- 年龄问题可能会成为你的顾虑之一  - 是
- you might consider that a possibility. - Yeah.
更不用说你还是个学生
Quite apart from the fact that you're a student
我并不想逼你做任何事 Cross小姐
I'm not trying to pressure you into anything, Miss Cross.
我很惊讶你这么直接地提出这件事
I'm surprised you brought it up so bluntly.
我只想确认一下
I just want to make sure -
- 我们已经是好朋友了 对吗  - 对
- We've become friends, haven't we? - Yes.
很好
Good.
还有 呃
And, um...
事实是 我们都不清楚
the - the truth is neither one of us has the slightest idea...
这段关系会怎么发展
where this relationship is going.
我们不可能预测未来
We can't predict the future.
我们没有关系 Max
We don't have a relationship, Max.
- 但我们是朋友  - 是的 我们只能是朋友
- But we're friends. - Yes, and that's all we're going to be.
这就是我说的"关系"呀
That's all I meant by "Relationship."
要我给你拿本字典吗
You want me to grab a dictionary?
不 我只是想确保彼此明白对方的想法
No. I just want to make sure that we understand each other.
我懂了
I understand.
我不够吸引你
You're not attracted to me.
生活就是这样
C'est la vie.
Max 你才十五岁
Max, you're 15 years old.
还没到谈吸引力的年纪
Attraction doesn't enter into it.
你说什么就什么吧
If you say so.
我想说的是
Look, all I'm getting at is that -
我从来没有遇到过像你这样的人
that I've never met anyone like you.
所以你想怎样看待它的意义都可以
So you can take that for whatever it's worth.
我也从来没遇到过像你这样的人
I think I can safely say I've never met anyone like you either.
没有吗
You haven't, have you?
要不要握个手
Want to shake hands?
我很高兴我们有这次谈话
I'm glad we had this conversation.
我也是
So am I.
冲突
Max Fischer全新力作
我不能装窃听器 他们每天都会搜我的身
I can't wear a wire. They're feeling me up every day.
没事的 Frank 你会受到全方位保护的
Oh, come on, Frank. You'll have complete protection.
是吗 这话我之前也听过
Yeah, I've heard that one before.
- 我要去给计时收费表里投一枚硬币  - 坐下 Frank
- I gotta put a dime in the meter. - Sit down, Frank.
Joe 帮Serpico警官给计时表里投个硬币
Joe, go put a dime in the meter for Officer Serpico.
听着 Serpico 如果你愿意在法庭上作证
Look, Serpico, if you agree to testify in open court -
- 不  - 不什么
- No! - No, what?
不 我不会作证的
No, I'm not gonna testify.
走走走
Go, go, go.
那你就要上交你的手枪和警徽
I'll expect your gun and your badge on my desk -
- 答应我一件事 O'Reilly  - 说
- Promise me one thing, O'Reilly. - Name it.
你要从头到尾一直负责
That you're gonna follow this thing all the way to the end...
我这条线
of the line... where I got to be.
那就帮点忙吧
So help me God.
- 有人从那栋楼里出来了  - 有消息
- Someone coming out of the building. - I've got something!
- 等等 这可能就是他  - 街对面有动静
- Wait. This could be it. - There's action across the street.
- 就是他  - 是雪人
- Yeah, it's him. - It's Snowman.
- 他要上高架火车了  - 抓住他
- He's getting on the el train! - Take him!
- 奶油卷饼那句怎么回事  - Max
- What happened to the cannoli line? - Max -
你应该说 "算了 Sanchez
You're supposed to say, "Forget about it, Sanchez.
那老家伙爱吃奶油卷饼"
The old man likes his cannolis."
好了 我是犯了个小错误
Look, I made a mistake, all right?
但这完全没有影响
It didn't make any difference anyway.
我没打算继续追究 但别以为这无所谓
Hey, I'm letting it go, but don't say it doesn't matter.
- 所有台词都是字斟句酌的  - 一边去
- Every line matters. - Get off my back!
别把我的剧搞砸了
Don't fuck with my play!
- 你这个混蛋  - 喂 分开 快分开
- You fucking cocksucker - - Hey, break it up. Break it up.
我要杀了你
I'm gonna kill you.
Max Max
Max. Max.
我觉得今晚的表演特别优秀
I thought the acting tonight was excellent.
谢谢 其实它彩排的时候更完美
Thanks. Well, it was better in rehearsals.
我晚点再跟你见面 爸 我要赴一个晚餐
I'll catch up with you later, Dad. I got a dinner to go to.
- 是吗  - 嗯 就跟演员和工作人员
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah. Cast and crew only.
- 要给你点钱吗  - 不用了 爸
- Oh. You need some money? - No, Dad.
- 那巴掌怎么样  - 挺好的
- Well, how was the slap? - It was good.
他来了 Max 剧超级棒
There he is. Max, that was great.
我很高兴你能来
I'm so glad you could come.
我想让你认识一下我的朋友Peter Flynn 这是Max Fischer
I want you to meet a friend of mine. Peter Flynn, Max Fischer.
你好
Hi.
这家伙是谁
Who's this guy?
Peter
Peter.
我很喜欢你的戏 真的很酷
I really liked your play. It was really cool.
是啊
Yeah.
你的鼻子怎么了
What happened to your nose?
- 我被人揍了一拳  - 噢 天
- I got punched in the face. - Oh, boy.
你的理由是什么
What's your excuse?
- 嗨 大作家  - 你好吗
- Hey, author. - How you doing?
- 干得漂亮  - 谢谢
- Nice job. - Thank you.
今晚能见到你父亲吗
Gonna get to meet your dad tonight?
不 他今晚值班
Oh, no. The old man's on call.
Blume 我想让你见见Cross小姐
Mr. Blume, I'd like you to meet Miss Cross -
还有这位我还不知道名字的先生
And I didn't catch this young gentleman's name.
我挺喜欢你的护士服的
I like your nurse's uniform, guy.
这是手术室工作服
These are O.R. Scrubs.
手术室吗
"O.R." They? -
这套衣服和这个餐厅格格不入
Well, they're totally inappropriate for the occasion.
我并不知道我们要出来吃晚餐
Well, I didn't know we were going to dinner.
因为并没有邀请你
That's because you weren't invited.
算了 Max
Take it easy, Max.
是你给他点的威士忌和苏打
You were the one that ordered him a whiskey and soda.
那有什么错
So what's wrong with that?
我能写一出好剧
I can write a hit play.
为什么就不能喝点小酒放松一下
Why can't I have a little drink to unwind myself?
告诉我 卷毛 你跟Cross小姐是怎么认识的
So, tell me, curly, how do you know Miss Cross?
- 我们一起在哈佛读书  - 噢 挺好的
- We went to Harvard together. - Oh, that's great.
我自编自导了一出很棒的剧
I wrote a hit play and directed it.
所以我也没落下风
So I'm not sweating it either.
这里结账 谢谢
Can we get a check, please?
- 你以为你在干嘛  - 结账呀
- What do you think you're doing? - Getting the check.
不用你来 抱歉
No, you're not. Excuse me.
我很感谢你为我们调整安排
I just want to thank you for accommodating us.
其实原先我们只有三个人
You see, we only thought we were going to be three...
但有人不请就自来了 我很抱歉
but, uh, someone invited himself along, so I apologize.
- 不客气 先生  - 好
- Quite all right, sir. - Okay.
很好
Very well.
你这样很没礼貌 Max
You're being rude, Max.
- 我没有  - 你就是
- No, I'm not. - Yes, you are.
我没有 我只是想弄明白
No, I'm not. I'm just trying to
你为什么会带这位先生来看我的剧
figure out why you brought this gentleman to my play...
以及让他出席这顿没有受邀的晚餐
and my dinner, which was invitation only.
你需要我把奶油壶递给你吗 医生
Would you like me to pass you the creamer, Doc?
好的 谢谢
Yes, please.
- 你有毛病吗  - 你才有毛病吧
- What is wrong with you? - What is wrong with you?
你伤了我的心 今晚对我来说很重要
You hurt my feelings! This night was important to me!
我怎么伤你心了
How did I hurt your feelings?
我的天
Oh, my God!
我写了这么好的剧
I wrote a hit play!
而且我爱上你了
And I'm in love with you.
在这再加一点
Put that a little bit there.
嗨
Hi.
你刚才是躲在那儿吗
Were you hiding over there?
我不想打断课堂
Uh, I didn't want to disrupt class.
你这儿画的是什么
What's that you're painting?
这是 一只水母
That's a - a jellyfish.
我能为你做什么 Blume先生
What can I do for you, Mr. Blume?
Max想跟你谈谈
Max wants to talk to you.
谈什么
What for?
他想道歉吧 应该
To apologize, I think.
到这边聊吧
Should we talk over here?
- 他派你来的吗  - 是的
- He sent you? - Yeah.
你是他的信使吗
Are you his messenger?
不 我是他朋友
No, I'm his friend.
你是对的 我不应该让他喝酒的
You were right. I should not have allowed him to drink.
我觉得我不应该再见Max了
I don't think I should see Max anymore.
他一定不想听到这个消息
Well, he's not gonna like the sound of that.
他不想 我知道 但
No. No, I know, but...
我觉得他太依赖我了
I think I let him get too attached.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我觉得你已经尽力做好了
Well, I think you did your best.
转告他我很抱歉
Tell him I'm sorry.
好吧
Okay.
你的名字是
What is your first name?
Rosemary
Rosemary.
你的呢
What's yours?
Herman
Herman.
他给你写了封信
He wrote you a letter.
亲爱的Cross小姐
Dear Miss Cross...
我想借此机会 正式向你
I would like to take this opportunity to formally apologize...
为二十三号晚上的事情道歉
for the events of the night of the 23rd.
我不习惯喝酒
I'm not accustomed to drinking alcohol.
如果有时间的话
Please do me the service of coming
请你出席我新负责的项目的开幕式
to the unveiling of a new venture I've undertaken.
希望你能到场
I hope you will attend, if possible.
我还是你的朋友 Max Fisher
I remain your friend, Max Fischer.
希望你能到场
我还是你的朋友
停止音乐 也别拍照了
Cut the music, and no more pictures.
- 几点了 Alan  - 一点十五分
- What time is it, Alan? - 1:15.
借过一下 先生 把薯片放下 Buchan
Excuse me, gentlemen. Hey, lay off the chips, Buchan.
你有看到她吗
Did you see her?
- 她没来这  - 去她的教室看看
- She's not here. - Well, go check her classroom.
我要继续锯掉这些树吗
Shall I go ahead and take care of this tree?
- 稍等几分钟  - 这里在干嘛 Maxie
- Let's wait a few minutes. - What's going on here, Maxie?
你好 Beck教练 很高兴见到你
Oh, hey, Coach Beck. Good to see you.
我们要在这建一个新的水族馆
This is where we're putting in the new aquarium.
我现在是委员会的负责人 如果你相信的话
I'm in charge of the committee, if you can believe it.
这里是我的棒球场
This is my baseball diamond.
我知道 我相信很快它就会被移远一点的了
Yeah, I know, and I believe it's being relocated a few feet over.
水族馆里真的会有食人鱼吗
Is it true the aquarium will have piranhas?
你从哪听来的
Where did you hear that?
我的线人暗示了这个可能性
My source indicated that it was a possibility.
是真的 不过食人鱼是一种很狡猾的生物
Yes, it's true, but piranhas are a very tricky species.
Max
Max?
抱歉 George
Excuse me, George.
- 坏消息  - 是什么
- Bad news. - What's the story?
- 她今天找人代课了  - 为什么
- She had a substitute teacher today. - Why?
- 可能她生病了吧  - 她肯定没有生病
- I guess she got sick. - You know she's not sick.
把电话给我
Give me the phone.
Janet 我是Max Fisher Blume先生在吗
Janet. Max Fischer. Is Mr. Blume there?
他在哪
Well, where is he?
该死的 他应该到这的
Goddamn it. He's supposed to be here.
我才不关心那些梭鱼
I don't give a shit about the barracudas...
但我就他妈要它建起来
but fuck it, I'm building it anyway.
Max
Max!
这些该死的电锯是哪来的
Where are those damn chain saws coming from?
- 他在那  - Max Max
- He's right over there! - Max! Max!
你好 Guggenheim博士
Oh, hello, Dr. Guggenheim.
你他妈以为你在干嘛
What the hell do you think you're doing?
我们在进行一个资金募集的
We're having a fund-raiser for the - -
把那鬼东西关掉
Turn that damn thing off!
告诉我这不是真的
Tell me this isn't happening.
Guggenheim博士
Dr. Guggenheim, I'd rather
我不太想在我的团队面前谈这事
not have this conversation in front of my crew.
十月
第七章
...chapter seven.
还有一件事 今天有位新同学加入我们
One more thing. We have a new student with us today.
他叫Max Fischer
His name's Max Fischer...
现在想跟大家说几句话
and he's actually asked to say a few words to the class.
Max 你想到台上来讲吗
Max, do you want to take it away?
好的 谢谢
Sure. Thanks very much.
我就是想介绍一下自己
I just wanted to introduce myself.
我叫Max Fischer
I'm Max Fischer.
之前就读于拉什莫尔学院
I'm a former student of Rushmore Academy...
最近被开除了
which I recently got expelled from.
这是我第一次在公立学校上课
This is my first time in a public school.
你们可能会觉得
I know you probably think
我是含着金钥匙出生的
I was born with a silver spoon in my mouth...
但我并不是什么富家子弟
but I'm no elitist.
我觉得这里有很多不错的设施
I think you've got some great facilities...
我很希望
and I'm really looking forward
能充实地在格罗弗克利夫兰学习
to making the best of it here at Grover Cleveland.
补充一句
One footnote.
我注意到你们这儿没有成立击剑队
I notice you don't have a fencing team.
我会尽我所能给你们创办一个
Well, I'm gonna try my hardest to start one up for you guys.
- Max  - 什么
- Max? - Yes?
我 我是Margaret Yang 我是Whitney老师班上的
I. I'm Margaret Yang. I'm in Mrs. Whitney's class.
我只想告诉你我很喜欢你的发言
I just wanted to tell you that I liked your speech.
谢谢
Thank you.
我从来没听说过
I don't think I've ever heard
有人会主动要求在班里演讲的
of anyone asking to give a speech in class before.
没有吗 真可惜
No? How unfortunate.
有钱人的标签可能会让某些人觉得不爽
The silver spoon remark might rub some people the wrong way.
- 但我觉得我  - 什么意思
- But I think I know - - What do you mean?
- 就是  - 你知道吗
- Well - - You know what?
我要去上课了 晚点再聊吧 Chang小姐
I gotta go into class in here. I'll see you later, Ms. Chang.
格罗弗克利夫兰 中学
预备
En garde!
Janet 我是Max Fischer 他在吗
Janet. Max Fischer. Is he in?
什么
Yeah?
好的
Okay.
- 嗨 Max 最近怎么样  - 很糟糕
- Hey, Max, how's it going? - Terrible.
告诉我 你那天去跟Cross小姐聊的时候
Tell me something. When you talked to Miss Cross the other day -
你有通话许可吗 抱歉
Do you have a telephone pass? Excuse me.
- 你有通话许可吗  - 等一下
- Do you have a telephone pass? - One second.
我必须跟你说 我不知道你看上她什么了
I gotta tell ya, I don't know what you see in her.
我 我觉得她不适合你
I-I don't think she's right for you.
这话是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我的意思是 她也没多漂亮
I mean, she's not that beautiful.
也不是很迷人
She's not that intriguing.
就 她身上有些特质
I mean, she has something
是很难琢磨的 但
that you can't put your finger on, but -
听着 Blume先生 你的评价很宝贵
Look, Mr. Blume, your comments are valuable,
但我们直接说重点吧
but let's get to the point.
- 孩子  - 她会再见我吗 会还是不会
- Son? - Will she see me again, yes or no?
- 不会  - 等等
- No. - Hang on.
我在讲电话
I'm talking on the telephone.
拜托 这样也太没礼貌了
Oh, come on. That's rude.
所有学生必须随时服从教职人员的搜查
喂 Fischer
Hey, Fischer.
你最好滚开 小鬼
You better beat it, sonny.
Fischer 其实我一直有关注你
You know, Fischer, I've been watching you.
爱卖弄 说个不停
Showboat. Always talkin'.
因为他妈妈长得不错就挑了个像Dirk那样的小子
Picking a kid like Dirk because his mother's a great piece...
但是一点便宜也没占到
and then getting nowhere.
像你做的任何事
Like everything you do.
盛大演出 毫无水花
Big show. No results.
你觉得在Calloway夫人的
What do you call getting a hand job from
捷豹后座手淫算什么
Mrs. Calloway in the back of her Jaguar?
一个扯淡的谎话
A fucking lie.
你以为我退学是因为水族馆的事吗
You think I got kicked out for just the aquarium?
不 是因为手淫的事
Nah. It was the hand job.
再告诉你一点 爽翻了
You want to know something else? It was worth it.
对不起 让你在上次晚餐里那么尴尬
I'm sorry I embarrassed you at dinner.
也请帮我转告那谁 我很抱歉
And please apologize to what's-his-name for me.
我会的
I will.
你还好吗
You okay?
挺好的 但是很想念拉什莫尔
Yeah, I'm fine, but I miss Rushmore.
我想念这里的季节变换
I miss the seasons.
看着树叶由黄变绿
Watching the leaves change.
顺便问问 图书馆什么时候关
By the way, what time does the library close?
我有本过期的书要还
I've got an overdue book to turn in.
这是你的笔迹 对吧
That is your handwriting, isn't it?
这本书是我十三岁那年
My husband gave me this book...
我丈夫来英国的时候给我的
when he came to visit England when I was 13.
赠予拉什莫尔学院图书馆
纪念 Edward Appleby
然后他去了拉什莫尔
And he went to Rushmore,
他去世以后 我就把它捐给图书馆了
so when he died I gave it to the library here.
你总让我想起他 你知道吗
You remind me of him, you know?
我吗
I do?
怎么会
How?
嗯
Well...
你是拉什莫尔养蜂社的成员 是不是
you were a member of the Rushmore Beekeepers, weren't you?
对 我是社长
Yeah. I was president of them.
那社团是他创办的
He founded that club.
你觉得我们还能做朋友吗 Cross小姐
Do you think we can be friends again, Miss Cross?
完全纯粹柏拉图式的朋友
In-In a strictly platonic way?
当然
Of course I do.
你觉得你能在格罗弗克利夫兰
Do you think you can make a go of it
好好努力安心学习吗
and settle down at Grover Cleveland?
背景音乐 <Here Comes My Baby> - Cat Stevens
能 不过我需要一个辅导老师
Yeah, but I need a tutor.
*在夜半的月光下*
*In the midnight moonlight*
*我会*
*I'll*
*只身走在漫漫长路*
*Be walking a long and lonely mile*
*每当这个时候*
*And every time I do*
*我会一直看着你的照片*
*I keep seeing this picture of you*
*我的宝贝来了*
*Here comes my baby*
*她出现了*
*Here she comes now*
*不出我所料*
*And that comes as no surprise to me*
浪潮
*身旁伴有别人*
*With another guy*
*我的宝贝来了*
*Here comes my baby*
*她出现了*
*Here she comes now*
*与她的爱人漫步 一切完美*
*Walkin' with a love With a love that's all so fine*
*她从来都不属于我*
*Never could be mine*
*无论我怎么尝试*
*No matter how I try*
*你身旁永远有人相伴*
*You never walk alone*
猫头鹰加油 走起
Fighting Owls, let's go!
*你永远都在讲电话*
*And you're forever talking on the phone*
*我尝试呼唤你的名字*
*I try to call you names*
加油
Let's go!
*但结果从来都一样*
*But every time it comes out the same*
*我的宝贝来了*
*Here comes my baby*
*她出现了*
*Here she comes now*
- 好的 还有什么  - Alan等你挑一只鸟
- Okay, what else do we got? - Alan's got the birds for your approval.
绿色的那只吧
I'll take the green one.
- 刀在这  - 太假了
- And here's the knife. - That's too fake.
- 你好 Max  - 你好
- Hi, Max. - Hello.
- 我忘了你叫什么  - Margaret Yang
- What's your name again? - Margaret Yang.
Margaret Yang 第七节课时你在干什么 Margaret Yang
Margaret Yang. What are you doing seventh period, Margaret Yang?
我要上吉他课
I have guitar lessons.
- 古典吉他还是 哪个流派的  - 摇滚
- Classical guitar or in what school? - Rock.
摇滚 那就好 你可以不上那节课了
Ro That's good. We can get you out of that.
请让我看看你不带眼镜的样子好吗
Could I see you without your glasses on, please?
记一下 Margaret下午3点30分剧院排演 Woody
Let's put Margaret down for 3:30 in the auditorium, Woody.
谢谢
Thank you.
记得带一张大头照过来
And-And bring a head shot, please.
你好 Herman
Hello, Herman.
- 你好吗 Rosemary  - 我很好 谢了
- How are you, Rosemary? - I'm fine, thanks.
我刚到家 吃了点零食
I just got home, and I'm having a little snack.
- 吃胡萝卜吗  - 是啊
- Having some carrots? - Yeah.
房子不错
Nice house.
是啊 但不是我的
Yeah. Um, it isn't mine.
我只是替别人看家
I'm just sort of house-sitting.
呃 你正在在这附近吗
Um... you were in the neighborhood?
Max今天安排了什么计划吗
Uh... did Max have something planned for us today?
去博物馆还是其他什么
A trip to the museum or something?
没有安排 他今天晚上有排练
No, I don't think so. I-I think he's rehearsing tonight.
哦 对了 他在准备他的新话剧
Oh, that's right. He's doing his new play.
他在格罗弗克利夫兰那真的适应得挺不错的
Yeah, he's really making a go of it over there at Grover Cleveland.
没错 他确实做的很好
Yeah, he's doing very well, isn't he?
你想吃一根萝卜吗
Do you want a carrot?
好啊 我尝一根吧
Yeah, I'll have one of those.
谢谢
Thank you.
我也许很快会再见你
Well, I'll probably be seeing you soon.
或者现在我们可以出去走一走 如果你想的话
Or we could go for a walk now, if you like.
当然
Sure.
天气还不错 不是吗
The weather's nice, isn't it?
有点冷
A little brisk.
我去加一件毛衣 马上回来
I'll just get a sweater. I'll be back in a minute.
Dirk
Dirk?
我知道你和那个老师的事了
I know about you and the teacher.
Max知道吗
Does Max know?
他不知道 我永远都不想让他知道
No, and I don't want him to know, ever.
我只要你马上停手
I just want it to stop right now.
你已经结婚了 Blume
You're a married man, Blume...
你本应该是他的朋友
and you're supposed to be his friend.
听着 Dirk 我是他的朋友
Look, Dirk, I am his friend.
是啊 像你这样的朋友 谁会要啊
Oh, yeah. And with friends like you, who needs friends?
开门
Unlock it!
Calloway小子
Little Calloway.
你帮错人了 Fischer不是你的好兄弟
You're standing up for the wrong guy. Fischer ain't your mate.
你在说什么 Buchan
What are you talking about, Buchan?
他想睡你妈妈
He thinks your mom's good for a bonk.
所以才选你做他的教友
That's the only reason he picked you as his chapel partner.
- 谁和你胡说八道的 - 他自己告诉我的
- Who sold you that crock? - He told me himself.
他说你妈在她那辆捷豹车后座上给他撸了
He says she gave him a hand job in the backseat of her bloody Jaguar.
Max从来不会说这种话
Max would never say that.
是啊 我想你是对的
Yeah. I suppose you're right.
毕竟 现在脑科医生的儿子
After all, the son of a brain doctor...
不需要去取悦别人了 是吧
doesn't need to impress anybody now, does he?
必须停止杀戮 兄弟 现在已经太疯狂了
The killing's gotta stop, esse. It's getting too loco.
- 不要再动枪了  - 老兄 是你疯了吧
- No more gats. - Nigger, you're the crazy one.
很多人想杀你
People be trying to kill you.
你的意思是打算缴械投降吗
Are you talkin' about you're gonna get rid of your gun?
时间到了 伙计
It's time, homey.
吻我 小Juan
Kiss me, Little Juan.
好了 然后他吻了她我们就下场 好吧
All right, then he kisses her and we're out. Okay.
那是给我的吗
Is that for me?
亲爱的Max 很抱歉地告诉你我偷偷发现了
Dear Max, I am sorry to say that I have secretly found out...
Blume先生和Cross小姐的外遇
that Mr. Blume is having an affair with Miss Cross.
我第一次怀疑这事
My first suspicions came when
是我看见他们在她房子前热吻的时候
I saw them Frenching in front of her house...
然后我又看到 当你在前廊睡午觉时
and then I knew for sure when they
他们在Blume先生家的泳池里裸泳
went skinny-dipping in Mr. Blume's swimming pool...
互相抚摸彼此下体
giving each other hand jobs
那时候我才确定他们之间有不一般的关系
while you were taking a nap on the front porch.
至于我为什么要现在告诉你
Why am I telling you this now?
因为你是那么好的一个朋友
Because you're such a good friend.
保重 哥们
Take care, pal.
真心的 Dirk Calloway
Fondly, Dirk Calloway.
天啊
God.
她怎么样 Herman
How was she, Herman?
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
她不错吧 我赌她不错
Was she good? I bet she was.
虽然我不知道 因为我从来没有上过她
Although, I wouldn't know 'cause I never screwed her.
在我睡午觉的时候裸泳
Going skinny-dipping while I took a nap.
"你还好吗 Max
"Are you comfortable, Max?
我就在外头 背着你 全身赤裸
I'll just, uh, be out back, nude,
享受来自你爱的女人的抚摸"
getting hand jobs from the woman you love."
我们从来没有裸泳
We never went skinny-dipping.
当然没有
Sure you didn't.
接下来你打算告诉我
And next you're gonna tell me
你没有恰好在凌晨2点走出她的家门吗
you didn't just walk out of her house at 2:00 in the morning.
我爱上她了
I'm in love with her.
我先爱上她的
Well, I was in love with her first.
还有你之前那堆废话
And all that crap about...
"我觉得她不怎么样
"I don't think she's that great.
她一点也不适合你 Max"
I don't think she's right for you, Max."
都是胡扯 是不是
That was all bullshit, wasn't it?
你觉得她爱你吗
Do you think she's in love with you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我向你保证她不爱你 永远都不会
Well, I guarantee you she's not, and she never will be.
Max
Max.
我拯救了拉丁语课
I saved Latin.
你又为她做过什么
What did you ever do?
背景音乐 <Jersey Thursday> - Donovan
在我的星球上
On the planet I come from...
太阳每年只出现一次
the sun only comes out once a year.
*在一小片彩色玻璃上*
*From a tiny piece of colored glass*
- 所以我的皮肤  - 打扰了
- That is why my skin  - Excuse me.
*我的爱诞生了*
*My love was born*
不好意思打扰了
Oh, I'm sorry.
我只是过来感谢你毁了我的生活
I just came by to thank you for wrecking my life.
*红色金色黄色是曙光的颜色*
*And reds and golds and yellows were the colors of the dawn*
Max 你在干什么
Max, what are you doing?
*夜晚为天空盖上*
*Night brought on its purple cloak*
*紫天鹅绒的披风*
*Of velvet to the sky*
*海鸥在低空旋转*
*And the gulls were wheeling,*
*盘旋在泽西岛的星期四*
*Spinning on Jersey Thursday*
你好 Blume夫人 我是Max Fisher
Hello, Mrs. Blume. This is Max Fischer.
我有一些关于你丈夫的消息
I have some information regarding your husband.
请在我的语音信箱留言回复
Please return my call on my voice
格罗弗克利夫兰高中 23号分机
mail: Grover Cleveland High School, extension 23.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
谢谢你能来见我
Thank you for meeting me.
不用谢
You're welcome.
你想来一份三明治吗
Would you like a sandwich?
好吧
All right.
有金枪鱼 花生酱和果酱口味
I have a tuna and peanut butter and jelly.
抱歉 都是很普通常见的食物
Sorry it's not something more exotic.
- 我要金枪鱼的  - 好的
- I'll take the tuna fish. - Okay.
牛奶还是苹果汁
Milk or apple juice?
有话直说吧
Get to the point.
好的
Okay.
你的丈夫
Your husband's
您准备在我们这住多久 Blume先生
And how long will you be staying with us, Mr. Blume?
无限期 我正在打离婚官司
Indefinitely. I'm being sued for divorce.
- 好极了 先生  - 嘿 矮子
- Very good, sir. - Yo, shorty.
我说 你能告诉我游泳池在哪吗
Say, can you tell me where the pool is located?
我想在吃了饭喝了酒之后游个泳
I might want to take a dip after I have dinner and hit the bar.
泳池在楼顶 先生
It's on the roof, sir.
*该死 该死*
*Dang, dang*
背景音乐 <A Quick One, While He's Away> - The Who
*该死 该死*
*Dang, dang*
拉什莫尔养蜂社
*大提琴 大提琴 大提琴 大提琴 大提琴 大提琴 大提琴 大提琴*
*Cello, cello, cello, cello, cello, cello, cello, cello*
*不敢相信*
*Can't believe it*
*是我看错了吗*
*Do my eyes deceive me*
*是我回到你的怀抱吗*
*Am I back in your arms*
*远离所有伤害*
*Away from all harm?*
*和你在一起就像 做梦一样*
*It's like a dream to be with you*
*再一次*
*Again*
*不敢相信我和你在一起*
*Can't believe that I'm with you*
*再一次*
*Again*
*你得到原谅了*
*You are forgiven*
Blume国际 埋弧焊钢管公司
*原谅你 原谅你*
*You are forgiven You are forgiven*
*原谅你 原谅 原谅*
*You are forgiven, forgiven, forgiven*
*原谅 原谅 原谅 原谅 原谅*
*Forgiven, forgiven, forgiven, forgiven, forgiven*
*你被原谅了*
*Know you're forgiven*
*拜托 宝贝*
*Come on, baby*
*知道你是谁*
*Know that you are*
*知道原谅你*
*Know you're forgiven*
*知道你曾被判缓刑*
*Know that you've been reprieved*
*宝贝*
*Baby*
*原谅你*
*You are forgiven*
他大概高1米6 重51公斤
He's about 5-foot-3, 112 pounds...
黑头发 戴眼镜 鹅蛋脸
black hair, glasses, oval face.
*原*
*For*
*你知道我原谅你了*
*You know you're forgiven*
*原谅你 原谅你*
*You are forgiven You are forgiven*
*原谅 知道原谅你了*
*Forgiven Know you're forgiven*
*原谅*
*Forgiven*
*知道原谅你了*
*Know you're forgiven*
谢谢你保释我 爸爸 你能把我载到拉什莫尔吗
Thanks for bailing me out, Dad. Can you drop me off at Rushmore?
我要去让他们解雇一个老师
I gotta go get a teacher fired.
那可不太明智 Max
I don't think that's wise, Max.
哇喔 你们要干什么 你们要干什么
Whoa! What are you doing? What are you doing?
这是私人领地 你是非法入侵
This is private property. You're trespassing!
什么 你疯了吗
What, are you crazy?
等一下
Wait a minute!
住手 可以暂时停火吗
Stop! Let's have a truce for a second.
等等 停火 停火
Wait! Truce! Truce!
这是怎么回事
What's this all about?
你有没有说过我妈妈给你撸了
Did you say my mom gave you a hand job?
- 什么  - 你说过吗
- What? - Did you say it?
谁告诉你这么荒谬的谎话
Who told you that goddamn lie?
算了 我知道谁说的
Never mind. I know who said it.
我会把刀刺入他的心脏
And I'm gonna stick a knife in his heart.
然后把他装进裹尸袋里送回爱尔兰
Then I'm gonna send him back to Ireland in a body bag.
他来自苏格兰
He's from Scotland.
告诉那个傻逼爱尔兰佬
Well, tell that stupid mick
他今天上了我的待处理清单
he just made my list of things to do today.
我会狠狠教训他一顿
I'm gonna pop a cap in his ass.
你收到了包裹
So you received the package?
很好
Good.
我只想通知你一下发生了什么事
I just wanted to inform you about what's going on.
我从来不觉得你会是告密者 Max
I never took you for an informer, Max.
那是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
"那是什么意思"
"What's that supposed to mean?"
她今天早上辞职了
She resigned this morning
在我收到你的小照片之前
before I even got your little snapshots.
所以你刚刚的捣蛋行为适得其反了
So your latest attempt at sabotage backfired.
但是她是你聘任过最好的老师
But she's one of the best teachers you've got.
你怎么能放她走
How could you let her go?
- 那你为什么要害她被开除  - 你这个没脑子的老笨蛋
- Why are you trying to get her fired? - You stupid old fool!
我是想要赢回她的心
I'm trying to win her back!
Cross小姐
Miss Cross?
你好 Max
Hi, Max.
- 需要帮忙吗  - 不用了 我可以的
- Need any help? - No, I have it.
- 该死  - 过来 让我看看
- Oh, damn. - Oh, here. Let me see.
不用了 拜托 你不应该来这儿的
No. Please, look. I don't think you should come in here.
听着 我很抱歉伤害了你的感情
Look, I'm sorry I hurt your feelings.
很抱歉我爱上了你的朋友而不是你 但是
I'm sorry I love your friend instead of you, but
拜托 Max
Please, Max
你真的相信你爱的是Blume而不是我
You honestly believe you love Blume instead of me?
是的
Yes.
请你原谅我没法把你这话当真
Well, you'll have to forgive me if I don't take your word for that.
- 打住吧  - Cross小姐
- Oh, stop. - Miss Cross.
听着 如果你还继续这样 我要发脾气了 我是认真的 不要
Listen, if you don't stop, I'm gonna lose it. I mean it! Don't -
太晚了
It's too late.
等一下 不要这样
Wait. Please.
- 我是因为你才被开除的  - 不是 是你自找的
- I got kicked out because of you. - No, you got kicked out -
拉什莫尔曾经是我的一切
Rushmore was my life.
现在是你了
Now you are.
不 我不是
No, I'm not.
你真的认为我们之间会发生什么吗
What do you really think is gonna happen between us?
你觉得我们会上床吗
Do you think we're gonna have sex?
那是一种下流肤浅的说法
That's a kind of cheap way to put it.
还是说你以前做过 不是吗
Not if you've ever fucked before, it isn't.
噢 上帝啊
Oh, my God.
你是怎么和你的朋友描述的
How would you describe it to your friends?
你是说你用手指让我高潮
Would you say that you'd fingered me?
还是说我给你撸了
Or maybe I could give you a hand job.
那样一切就结束了吗
Would that put an end to all of this?
请滚出我的教室
Please get out of my classroom.
Fisher 你这个满脸粉刺的小败类
Fisher, you spotty wee fuckup.
嗨 Magnus
Hey, Magnus.
最近用手搞得爽吗
Got any good hand jobs lately?
喂 Dirk 看谁在这
Hey, Dirk! Look who's here.
是你的后爸
It's your stepfather,
在等你妈妈来和他乱搞
waiting for your mom so that he can get a piece.
你的脑子和你的耳朵一样扭曲啊 Buchan
Your mind's as warped as your ear, Buchan.
不要搞事 老兄
Don't get nasty, brother.
我们搞定他了 Dirk
We got him, Dirk.
我们搞定他了
We got him.
Max
Max?
你好 Blume先生
Oh, hey, Mr. Blume.
你说想见我
You said you wanted to meet?
什么时候
Wh-When?
现在 你说你想结束这一切
Right now. You said you wanted to put an end to all this.
是的 我本来想
Oh, yeah. I , uh, was gonna
锯断那棵树 让它倒下来压住你
try and have that tree over there fall on you.
那棵大的
That big one?
就是
Yup.
那棵会把我压成煎饼的
It would have flattened me like a pancake.
是什么阻止了你
What stopped you?
我不知道 有什么意义吗
I don't know. What's the point?
她爱的是你
She loves you.
她是我的拉什莫尔 Max
She's my Rushmore, Max.
是啊 我知道 她也是我的
Yeah, I know. She was mine too.
背景音乐 <I
Am Waiting> - The Rolling Stones
*我在等待*
*I am waiting*
*哦 是的 哦 是的*
*Oh, yeah, oh, yeah*
十一月
*我在等待*
*I am waiting*
*哦 是的 哦 是的*
*Oh, yeah, oh, yeah*
*等待某人从某处出来*
*Waiting for someone to come out of somewhere*
*你坚持不了*
*You can't hold out*
*哦 是的 哦 是的*
*Oh, yeah, oh, yeah*
*你坚持不了*
*You can't hold out*
*哦 是的 哦 是的*
*Oh, yeah, oh, yeah*
*等待某人从某处出来*
*Waiting for someone to come out of somewhere*
- 你好  - 你好
- Hello. - Hi.
请问Max在家吗
I was wondering if Max was home.
*看到它过来却不知道它来自何方*
*See it come along and don't know where it's from*
他不在家
He's not in.
*哦 是的 你会明白的*
*Oh, yes, you will find out*
*好吧 这是常有的事*
*Well, it happens all the time*
*从我们的脑海里删除*
*It's censored from our minds*
抱歉
I'm sorry.
*你会明白*
*You'll find out*
*或快或慢*
*Slow or fast*
*哦 是的 哦 是的*
*Oh, yeah, oh, yeah*
*最后的最后*
*End at last*
*哦 是的 哦 是的*
*Oh, yeah, oh, yeah*
*等待某人从某处出来*
*Waiting for someone to come out of somewhere*
*在未来几年奋起*
*Stand up coming years*
*越来越害怕*
*And escalation fears*
*哦 是的 我们会明白的*
*Oh, yes, we will find out*
*好吧 像一块枯槁的石头*
*Well, like a withered stone*
*恐怖会刺穿你的骨头*
*Fears will pierce your bones*
*你会明白*
*You'll find out*
十二月
*哦 我们在等待*
*Oh, we're waiting*
晚安 Stan
Good night, Stan.
*哦 我们在等待*
*Oh, we're waiting*
圣诞节快乐 下次再见
Merry Christmas. See you next time.
有你在店里陪我真好 Max
It's been nice having your company here at the shop, Max.
你没有考虑过继续上学吗
You put any more thought into giving school another shot?
没有
No.
Max 我喜欢当一个理发师 我干这个很在行
Max, I like being a barber. I'm good at it.
但是我总希望你去试一试别的行业
But I always thought you'd try another line of work.
你说过要当参议员或者外交官
You talked about being a senator or a diplomat.
痴心妄想 爸爸
Pipe dreams, Dad.
我是一个理发师的儿子
I'm a barber's son.
晚餐见
See you at dinner.
- 你好 Dirk  - 你好 Max
- Hello, Dirk. - Hi, Max.
- 你有什么事吗  - 我也许该剪个头发
- What can I do for you? - I thought I might get a haircut.
我们关门了
We're closed.
我想和你道歉 那天向你扔石头
Well, I just want to say I'm sorry I threw rocks at you that day.
但是我该走了
But I guess I'll go now.
圣诞节快乐
Merry Christmas.
那里面是什么玩意
What in the hell's that?
Max Fischer
拉什莫尔校刊
1985-1997
你听到那个消息了吗
So, did you hear the news?
恐怕没有 我没怎么关注新闻了
I doubt it. I don't really follow the news anymore.
Guggenheim博士中风了
Dr. Guggenheim had a stroke.
我会寄一盒糖果给他
I'll send him a box of candy.
也许你应该去看看他
Maybe you ought to go visit him.
Guggenheim夫人
Mrs. Guggenheim?
你好 Max 快进来
Hello, Max. Come in.
见到你真好
It's so good to see you.
花真美 我会把它们放进水里养起来
Oh, these are glorious. I'll put them in some water.
坐吧
Have a seat.
我可以和Guggenheim博士打个招呼吗 还是他听不见
Should I say hello to Dr. Guggenheim or can he not hear me?
不 他能听见你
No, he can hear you.
你好 老家伙
Hey, old-timer.
我是Max Fisher
It's, uh, Max Fischer.
你可能听不见我的话
You probably can't hear me because...
我不知道你是不是大脑损伤了
I don't know if your brain is damaged or -
你想干什么
What do you want?
Nelson
Nelson?
这是他十天来说的第一句话
That's the first thing he's said in 10 days.
你觉得他认出我了吗
Do you think he recognized me?
应该没有吧
Oh, I don't think so.
是Fisher
It's Fischer.
再见了 希望你早日康复
See ya later. Bye. Hope you feel better.
你好 朋友
Hey, amigo.
谁打的黑眼圈啊
So, who gave you the shiner?
不是Ronny就是Donny
Either Ronny or Donny.
反正也分不出什么区别
Can't tell the difference anymore.
不管哪个 下手都不轻
Well, whichever one it was really clocked you.
是啊
Hmm.
孩子们不喜欢他们父母离婚
Kids don't like it when their parents get divorced.
- 我不怪他们  - 我也是
- I don't blame 'em. - Neither do I.
她怎么样了
How is she?
我真的不知道
I really wouldn't know.
- 为什么  - 我已经六个星期没见她了
- Why not? - I haven't seen her in six weeks.
发生什么了
What happened?
- 她走了  - 是啊
- She left? - Yeah.
她始终对那个死人无法忘怀
She's in love with a dead guy anyway.
Edward Appleby
Edward Appleby.
你知道
You know, uh...
她是很可爱 但是她太混乱了
she's sweet, but she's fucked-up.
再见 孩子
Adios, muchacho.
喂 你还好吧
Hey, are you okay?
呃 这几天我是有点孤单
Mmm. I'm a little bit lonely these days.
Max
Max?
你在这儿做什么
What are you doing here?
我不知道 上帝啊 那群人不知道从哪儿来的
I don't know. Jesus. They came at me out of nowhere.
- 突然冲过来了  - 什么
- It was so sudden. - What?
抱歉 我可以用一下你的电话吗 我刚被车撞了
I'm sorry. Can I use your phone? I just got hit by a car.
哦天呐 你你你还好吗
Oh, my God. A-A-Are you okay?
你说啥
Hmm? What did you say?
- 快进来  - 谢谢
- Come inside. - Thank you.
我去给你拿点药
I'm gonna get something for your head.
背景音乐 <Rue St. Vincent>  - Yves Montand
哦 这就是一切发生的地方
So, this is where it all happens.
- 一切什么事发生  - 我不知道
- All what happens? - I wouldn't know.
话说你为什么甩了Blume
So, why did you dump Blume?
和你无关
That's none of your business.
我知道和我无关
I know it's not.
但我刚被车撞了 现在脑子有点乱
But I just got hit by a car, and I'm a little confused right now.
我以为你为Blume而甩了我 然后我又听说
I mean, I thought you dumped me for Blume. Then I hear
我没甩你 因为我们从来没交往过
I never dumped you because we were never going out.
如果你和我聊会天的话就再好不过了
It would just help me if you talked to me for a minute.
告诉我发生了什么
Tell me what happened.
好吧
Okay.
首先 他已婚
A, he's married.
其次 他讨厌自己
B, he hates himself.
还有第三点
And C, Well...
他撞坏了你的自行车 对吧
he smashed up your bicycle, didn't he?
我以前的自行车 是的
My previous bicycle, yes.
什么样的人能做出那样的事啊
Well, what sort of a person does something like that?
我不知道
I don't know.
战争对男人有奇怪的影响
War does funny things to men.
他以为你甩了他是因为Edward Appleby
He thinks you dumped him because of Edward Appleby.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
意思就是 你住在他住过的房间里
Well, I mean, you live in his room...
四周都是他用过的东西 感觉有点
with all his stuff. It's kind of
我和他结过婚
I was married to him.
我知道
I know you were.
不过 我还是要说Edward一个指甲里的
Although, I will say that Edward has more spark and character...
闪光点 特质和想象力
and imagination in one fingernail...
就比Herman Blume整个人的还多
than Herman Blume has in his entire body.
一个死去的指甲
One dead fingernail.
是的
Right.
一个死去的指甲
One dead fingernail.
顺便问一下 他怎么死的
How did he die, by the way?
溺水
He drowned.
你母亲怎么死的
How did your mother die?
癌症
She got cancer.
忍住别动 好吗
Hold still for a moment, okay?
你很美
You're very pretty.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是假的血吗
Is this fake blood?
是的
Yes, it is.
你和Herman真是天生一对
You know, you and Herman deserve each other.
你们都幼稚得要命
You're both little children.
我送你出去
Let me show you the door.
我从窗户原路返回就行
I'll just go back out the window.
再见 Cross小姐
Good-bye, Miss Cross.
再见 Max
Good-bye, Max.
嘿
Hey.
我
I'm, uh
我很抱歉说你妈妈帮我手淫
I'm sorry about what I said about your mom giving me a hand job.
我知道 Max
I know, Max.
我也很抱歉Buchan揍你的时候我没去帮你
I'm sorry I didn't take your hand when Buchan kicked your ass.
嗯 没关系
Hey, uh, that's okay.
那是什么
What's that?
我不知道
I don't know.
漂亮的着陆
Nice landing.
你 你手里是什么
What's, uh - What's that you got there,
飞行计划还是什么
a little flight plan or something?
嗯 真不错
Hmm. Pretty good.
清晰度
南风 - 东南风
体育场
8%方向舵
快速着陆
停车场
马格南街
飞行调向22度
- 你认识Dirk Calloway吗  - 不认识
- Do you know Dirk Calloway? - I don't think so.
Dirk 这是Margaret Yang
Dirk, this is Margaret Yang.
我听说了你那个关于13号行动的科研项目
I, uh, heard about your science project on Action 13.
他们说海军想买走这个专利 那
They said the Navy wants to buy it from you. That's -
没有 没这回事了
No, not anymore.
为什么没有
Why not?
因为那是假的
Because it was a fake.
- 什么意思  - 我伪造了结果
- What do you mean? - I faked all the results.
- 为什么  - 因为结果没有如我所愿
- Why? - Because it didn't work.
我以为会是那样的 但结果不是
I thought it would, but it didn't.
你对我的态度真的很混蛋 你知道吗
You were a real jerk to me, you know that?
对不起 Margaret
I'm sorry, Margaret.
不管怎样 很高兴见到你
Well, anyway, nice to see you.
你想放一会吗
Do you want to take over for a while?
背景音乐 <The Wind> - Cat Stevens
帮我记一下
Take dictation, please.
放风筝社团的潜在候选人
Possible candidates for Kite Flying Society.
*我倾听着吹入我灵魂的风声*
*I listen to the wind to the wind of my soul*
David Connors Murray Marshall
David Connors. Murray Marshall.
Greg Holloway Duncan Wright
Greg Holloway. Duncan Wright.
Margaret Yang Woody Jackson Shoeshine Pickens
Margaret Yang. Woody Jackson. Shoeshine Pickens.
*我将善终于何处 唯上帝知晓*
*Where I'll end up Well, I think only God really knows*
*我安坐在落日上*
*I've sat upon the setting sun*
*但从未 从未 从未 从未*
*But never, never, never, never*
*我从未渴求甘霖*
*I never wanted water once*
*从未 从未 从未*
*No, never, never, never*
*我倾听自己的声音*
*I listen to my words*
*但它们都坠落远去*
*But they fall far below*
谢谢你来见我 Blume先生
Thanks for meeting me, Mr. Blume.
你要我做什么
What can I do for you?
*我随音乐引领我去到内心所向之地*
*I let my music take me where my heart wants to go*
这是什么
What's this?
全勤奖
守时奖
*我在恶魔之湖游弋*
*I swam upon the devil's lake*
这是全勤奖和守时奖
That's the Perfect Attendance Award and the Punctuality Award.
*但从未 从未 从未 从未*
*But never, never, never, never*
我在拉什莫尔获得的
I got those at Rushmore.
*我绝不会再重蹈覆辙*
*I'll never make the same mistake*
我想你可以选择你比较喜欢的
I thought you could choose which one you like more...
然后你戴那个 我戴另一个
and you could wear that one, and I could wear the other.
*从未 从未 从未*
*No, never, never, never*
我选守时奖
I'll take Punctuality.
好的
Okay.
过来
Come here.
谢谢
Thank you.
进去吧
Come on inside.
哎哟哟 看看这是谁来了
Well, well, well, well. Look what the cat dragged in.
抱歉回来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
没关系
That's okay.
我想让你见个人
I want you to meet someone.
Blume先生 这是我父亲 Bert Fischer
Mr. Blume, this is my father, Bert Fischer.
很高兴见到你 Fischer先生
Nice to meet you, Mr. Fischer.
Fischer先生是我父亲的名字 请叫我Bert
Now Mr. Fischer was my father's name. Call me Bert, please.
- 好的 Bert  - Max说你需要剪头发
- Okay, Bert. - So, Max tells me you need a haircut.
看得出来 你坐下来 我们来看看吧
I can see that. Why don't you sit down, and we'll have a look.
我不确定 Bert
I don't know, Bert.
别担心 Blume先生 这个过程相对来说并不痛
Don't worry, Mr. Blume. It's a relatively painless procedure.
或许我们还要刮个胡子
Maybe we'll throw in a shave as well.
好了 你喜欢你的胡子吗
Okay. Are you fond of that mustache?
你觉得还想留一段时间吗
Do you think you want to keep it for a while?
- 顺便问一句 你身家多少  - 我不知道
- How much are you worth, by the way? - I don't know.
- 超过一千万吗  - 嗯 应该是吧
- Over 10 million? - Yeah, I guess so.
- 很好很好  - 为什么
- Good, good. - Why?
因为我们将需要全部
'Cause we're gonna need all of it.
背景音乐 <Oh Yoko> - John Lennon
*在午夜时分*
*In the middle of the night*
*在午夜时分我呼唤你的名字*
*In the middle of the night I call your name*
*喔 洋子*
*Oh, Yoko*
*我将令你神魂颠倒*
*My love will turn you on*
放风筝社团
联合创始人
*喔 洋子*
*Oh, Yoko*
Cross 小姐
诚挚地邀请您参加
Herman J.Blume海洋气象台动工仪式
星期四 下午1点
便装出席 提供茶点 音乐
她不会来了 对吧
She's not coming, is she?
看起来不太妙
Hmm. Doesn't look good.
但别担心
But don't worry.
别这样 Herman
Come on, Herman.
- 操 我在这儿瞎搞什么呢  - 嘿
- Shit. What am I doing here? - Hey!
- 走开 走开  - 该死
- Scatter. Scatter. - Damn it!
你他妈是怎么赚了那么多钱的
How in the hell did you ever get so rich?
动不动就轻言放弃
You're a quitter, man!
我为这花了八百万美元
I paid eight million dollars for this.
这就是你所能付出的极限了吗
And that's all you're prepared to spend?
韦氏斯莫利女校
Cross小姐
很遗憾你那天
I'm, uh, sorry you couldn't make it
没能去参加我们的动工仪式
to our little groundbreaking the other day.
太可惜了 毕竟那是为你建的
It's kind of a shame since he's building it for you.
我从没要求任何人为我建一座水族馆
Well, you know, I never asked anyone to build me an aquarium.
真不知道那谣言是怎么开始的
I'm not quite sure how that rumor got started.
我也不知道
Me neither.
你觉得Edward Appleby会为你建一座水族馆吗
You think Edward Appleby would have built one for you?
我觉得他会的 如果他有那么多钱的话
Yeah, I think he would have, if he'd had the money.
我也是这么想的
That's what I thought.
Blume比你预想的
Blume's got a bit more spark and vitality
更有闪光点和活力 对吧
than you expected, doesn't he?
我以为这都是你的主意
I thought the aquarium was your idea.
我把这个主意送给我朋友了
Well, I gave it to my friend.
- 十五个炸药吗  - 是的
- Fifteen sticks? - Yes, please.
还有
And...
你可以把订单发给亚利桑那州图森市的
could you make the order out to Ready Demolition...
准备爆破公司吗
Tucson, Arizona?
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
确保这些别被弄湿
Make sure these don't get wet.
三点十五分见
I'll see you at 3:15.
- 你去哪儿  - 拉什莫尔
- Where are you going? - Rushmore.
我还有最后一件未完成的事要去做
I've got one last piece of unfinished business to attend to.
- Fischer 你他妈的  - 嗨 Magnus
- Fischer, you fuck! - Hello, Magnus.
我本该打到你另一只耳朵的
I'd have shot you in the other ear,
不过那只很早以前就被炸掉了
but it got blown off a long time ago.
另外 我们现在两清了
Besides, now we're even.
别高兴得太早 我的好兄弟
Not for long, Kemo Sabe.
走着瞧
We'll see.
我有个提议
I got a proposition for you.
你可以把它插进你妈妈的屁股里 你个小混蛋
Well, you can stick it up your mother's ass, you little prick.
我得承认 Magnus
I gotta hand it to you, Magnus.
你算是能说会道的
You've got a way with words.
你想演戏吗
You want to be in a play?
那是什么狗屁东西
What's all that shite?
没什么
Nothing.
我只是觉得你很适合那个角色
I just think you're right for the part.
天堂与地狱
Max Fisher新剧修订稿
已注册剧作家协会
我一直都想出演你他妈的剧
I always wanted to be in one of your fucking plays.
我知道你想 哥们
I know you did, mate.
一月
好激动人心啊 我儿子Max写的剧本
This is gonna be exciting. My son Max wrote it.
靠 我要给医院打电话
Oh, boy. I gotta call the hospital.
抱歉 请问你是英语老师Whitney小姐吗
Excuse me. Are you Mrs. Whitney, the English teacher?
是的
Yes.
你好 我是William Yang Margaret Yang的爸爸
Hi. I'm William Yang, Margaret Yang's father.
- 很高兴见到你  - 这是我妻子 Lucille
- Nice to meet you. - This is my wife, Lucille.
你好
Hello.
那孩子这是要烧了这地方啊
That kid's gonna burn this place down.
肯定会的
You better believe it.
那些计划从没正式提交到市里过
Well, the plans were never formally submitted to the city.
- 应该要提交吗  - 我想是的
- Were they supposed to be? - I assume so.
那现在也晚了
Too late now.
Brooks和Donovan警员
Officers Brooks and Donovan...
在格罗弗克利夫兰高中请求增援
requesting additional units at Grover Cleveland High School.
增援确认
Units responding, identify.
大纲 让我看下 翻过去 翻过去
The program. Let me look at that. Turn it. Turn it.
可以了
That's enough.
- 借过 坐这里  - 谢谢
- Excuse me. Right here. - Thanks.
嗨 Herman
Hi, Herman.
看来是Max捣的鬼
Looks like Max pulled a fast one on us.
非常感谢大家
Thank you very much.
我一般不这样 但这出戏剧对我很重要
I don't usually do this, but this play means a lot to me...
所以我想先发个言
and I wanted to make a dedication.
我只想说
So, I'll just say that
这出戏剧是为了纪念我的母亲
this play is dedicated to the memory of my mother...
Eloise Fischer
Eloise Fischer...
和Edward Appleby 一个朋友的朋友
and to Edward Appleby, a friend of a friend.
还有你们会在座位底下发现
Also, you'll find a pair of safety glasses and some earplugs...
一副护目镜和几只耳塞
underneath your seats.
请随意使用 谢谢大家
Please feel free to use them. Thank you very much.
B连 我是T7 听得到吗
Bravo Company, this is Tango 7. Do you copy?
我们命令美国军方采取措施
We order the military forces of the United States to take action
这是一场不同的战争
This is a different kind of war.
我们在取得进展 进展 进展 进展
We are making progress, progress, progress, progress.
你打头阵 冲浪小子
Take point, Surf Boy!
你来这儿多久了 士兵
How long you been in country, soldier?
我不在这儿 中士
I ain't even here, Sergeant.
我在怀俄明州夏延市
I'm in Cheyenne, Wyoming.
你说得真对 老兄
Right on, brother.
行动 Esposito
Let's rock, Esposito!
重复一遍 行动
I repeat, let's rock!
大家冲啊
Let's rock and roll!
准备射击 冲浪小子
Lock and load, Surf Boy!
快趴下
Nape it, now!
Fischer
Fischer!
我没事 冲冲冲冲
I'm okay. Go, go, go, go.
幕间休息
- 该死的  - 放轻松 Dirk
- Damn it! - Take it easy, Dirk.
- 我们还有多少时间 Wood  - 两分钟
- How much time do we got, Wood? - Two minutes.
好的 快再拿点番茄酱给我
All right. Bring me some more ketchup very quickly, please.
- 特效组  - 看起来肯定很蠢
- Effects! - This is gonna look stupid.
不会的 会很逼真的
No, it's not. It's gonna look real.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
这杯也拿着 好吗
Hold this one too, okay?
你觉得Max的最新作品如何
So, what do you think of Max's latest opus?
很好
It's good.
不过还是希望有个大团圆结局
But let's hope it's got a happy ending.
再见 Esposito
Adios, Esposito.
再见 中士
Adios, Sarge.
为冲浪小子祈祷
Say a prayer for Surf Boy...
不论他在哪儿
wherever he is.
永远忠诚 战士 永远忠诚
Semper fi, soldier. Semper fi.
荣光已逝
Sic transit gloria.
或许哪天我们会再见面
Maybe we'll meet again someday...
当战争结束的时候
when the fighting stops.
把他们打好标签然后装袋 小子们 我们要走了
Tag 'em and bag 'em, cherries! We're movin' out!
*我不知道 但曾经听说*
*I don't know, but I've been told*
你好 Esposito
Hello, Esposito.
你愿意嫁给我吗 Le-Chahn
Will you marry me, Le-Chahn?
当然
You bet I will.
那是我儿子 那是我的Maxie
That's my son. That's my Maxie.
我只是没想到会在这见到你
I just didn't expect to see you here.
Max给你发了邀请函吗
Did Max send you an invitation?
是的 还告诉我要戴领带
Yeah, and he told me to wear a tie.
- 祝贺你啊 Max  - 谢谢 Yang太太
- Congratulations, Max. - Thank you very much, Mrs. Yang.
其实两年前我写过另一个版本
I, uh, actually wrote a different version of the play two years ago...
但在拉什莫尔的时候没法演出
but I couldn't get it done over at Rushmore.
- 哦真的吗 为什么  - 太政治化吗
- Oh, really? Why? - Too political?
不 一个小孩在排练的时候被炸飞了手指
No, a kid got his finger blown off during rehearsals.
晚上好啊 Fischer一家 你们好
A very good evening to you, Fischers. Hi.
Cross小姐 我想向你介绍我的父亲 Bert Fischer
Miss Cross, I'd like for you to meet my father, Bert Fischer.
他是个理发师
He's a barber.
这是我朋友 Rosemary Cross
This is my friend, Rosemary Cross.
- 你好 Rosemary  - 终于见到您了很高兴 Bert
- Hello, Rosemary. - Nice to meet you at last, Bert.
Blume先生你认识的
Of course you know Mr. Blume.
我想向大家介绍Yang先生和Yang太太
I'd also like everyone to meet Mr. And Mrs. Yang.
- 这是Margaret  - 你好 Margaret
- This is Margaret. - Hello, Margaret.
很高兴见到你 Cross小姐
It's nice to meet you, Miss Cross.
我很惊讶他们真的让他在舞台上搭了营火
I'm surprised they let him build a real campfire on the stage.
明显是个安全隐患啊
It's clearly a safety hazard.
去年他还想养食人鱼呢
Well, last year he tried to raise piranhas.
嗯 我知道
Yeah, I know he did.
你觉得如何 Littlejeans先生
What did you think, Mr. Littlejeans?
有史以来最棒的剧
Best play ever, man.
我认为这是一场很真实的表演
I thought it was a very realistic performance.
是么 Fischer打断了我一半的台词
Yeah? Fischer stepped over half my bloody lines.
有点意思 我都没注意
That's funny. I didn't notice.
Blume先生 Ronny和Donny觉得军校怎么样
Mr. Blume, how are Ronny and Donny enjoying military school?
他们很喜欢
They love it.
幸运的混蛋
Lucky bastards.
我猜你是个神经外科医生
I understand you're a neurosurgeon.
不 我是个理发师 不过很多人都会猜错
No, I'm a barber. But a lot of people make that mistake.
你今晚真棒 Margaret
You were incredible tonight, Margaret.
- 你就是那个可怜的女孩  - 谢谢
- You were that poor girl. - Thank you.
我喜欢你在直升机要起飞的时候
I loved it when you grabbed onto the bottom of the chopper
紧紧抓住直升机底部的那段
as it was taking off.
- 那完全是即兴发挥  - 我知道
- That was totally improvised. - I know.
- 我可以问你个问题吗  - 当然
- Can I ask you a question? - Of course.
你会学澳洲口音吗
Can you do an Australian accent?
我正在写一个发生在澳洲的剧
I'm working on something that's set in the outback.
我真的很想庆祝一下
I really feel like celebrating, you know?
你想跳舞吗
Would you care to dance?
哦是的 我很愿意
Oh, yes, I-I would love to.
- 很好  - 来吧
- Great. - Come on.
你看上去不错 Bert
You're looking good, Bert.
你好 Blume先生
Hello, Mr. Blume.
你好 Margaret 我可以和你跳吗
Hello, Margaret. May I cut in?
我还没机会和你的新女友跳一支舞
I haven't had a chance to cut a rug with your new girlfriend yet.
哎哟 新女友
Ah, new girlfriend.
对 我就是
Yes, I am.
去找你自己的舞伴吧 Blume先生 我心有所属了
Find your own dance partner, Mr. Blume. I'm spoken for.
不 没关系的
No, it's okay.
他是我的朋友
He's my friend.
你成功做到了
Well... you pulled it off.
是啊 还过得去
Yeah, it went okay.
至少没人受伤
At least nobody got hurt.
除了你
Except you.
不 我没怎么受伤
No, I didn't get hurt that bad.
快 你们俩 跳起来啊
Come on, you two. Shake a leg.
你想跳舞吗
Would you like to dance?
想 但是
Yeah, but
看看DJ能不能放一些更加
Here, let's see if the deejay can play something with a little more
Reuben
Reuben!
天堂与地狱舞会
背景音乐 <Ooh La La> - Face
*可怜又年迈的爷爷*
*Poor old Granddad*
*我嘲笑他说的每一句话*
*I laughed at all his words*
*以为他天生就苦大仇深*
*I thought he was a bitter man*
*他提到女人常用的伎俩*
*He spoke of women's ways*
*她们引诱你然后利用你*
*They'd trap you, then they use you*
*让你无法察觉堕入其中*
*Before you even know*
*爱是盲目的而你太善良*
*For love is blind and you're far too kind*
*留心这个弱点别被看透*
*Don't ever Iet it show*
*真希望我之前就懂现在懂得的*
*I wish that I knew what I know now*
*在我更年轻的时候*
*When I was younger*
电波字幕组 欢迎您的加入
官方网站:www.dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@电波字幕组
*真希望我之前就懂现在懂得的*
*I wish that I knew what I know now*
*在我更强壮的时候*
*When I was stronger*
*康康舞是那么美好*
*The cancan's such a pretty show*
*会偷走你的心*
*Will steal your heart away*
*但后台又回归现实*
*But backstage back on Earth again*
*化妆间很灰暗*
*The dressing rooms are gray*
*她们很吸引人 让你觉得像个爷们*
*They come on strong and it ain't too long*
*但那不会长久*
*For they make you feel a man*
*但爱情是盲目的而你又会发现*
*But love is blind and you soon will find*
*你只是个小男孩*
*You're just a boy again*
*你想吻她的唇 却只亲到脸颊*
*When you want her lips, you get her cheek*
*于是你头昏脑涨 不知身在何方*
*Makes you wonder where you are*
*你想再来点甜头 她已倒头入睡*
*If you want some more, then she's fast asleep*
*留你一个人对着星星眨眼睛*
*Leaves you twinkling with the stars*
*可怜又年轻的乖孙*
*Poor young grandson*
*我无话可说*
*There's nothing I can say*
*你得重走我当年的老路*
*You'd have to learn just like me*
*历经同样的艰难和伤痕*
*And that's the hardest way*
*哦啦啦*
*Ooh la la*
*哦啦啦啦*
*Ooh la la la la*
*耶耶*
*Yeah, yeah*
*真希望我之前就懂现在懂得的*
*I wish that I knew what I know now*
*在我更年轻的时候*
*When I was younger*
*真希望我之前就懂现在懂得的*
*I wish that I knew what I know now*
*在我更强壮的时候*
*When I was stronger*